## **Ethan Lindsey**

Ames, IA | (515)-619-8081 | ethan.james.lindsey@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ejlindseycs | github.com/Ethan[Lindsey

Summary

A recent university graduate with aptitude for detailed analysis and logical reasoning. Strengths in math, computer theory, and problem-solving proven by experience tutoring university students. Excels at roles in mathematical or scientific fields especially involved with computer programming.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Music Technology

Iowa State University - GPA: 3.91

Experience

**Computer Science Tutor** 

January 2022 - December 2022

Iowa State University, Communications Building

Ames, IA

- Tutored 100+ clients on advanced programming practices and concepts.
- Collaborated with coworkers to find simple solutions for complex problems.
- Presented debugging processes on 500+ errors with  $\sim$ 95% success rate.
- Applied solid understanding of third and fourth-year level concepts.

**Student Worker** 

August 2021 - December 2021

Iowa State University, Exam Accommodations Center

Ames, IA

- Proctored 100+ students while supplying personalized accommodations.
- Evaluated sensitive confidential information discretely with integrity.
- Addressed 50+ critical issues with personalized solutions.

**Software Projects** 

Anthill

August 2022 - December 2022

- University senior design team project created using Flutter and Firebase.
- Contributed ~60% of the code including authentication, profile, and dashboard.
- Improved performance and security by reviewing team contributions.
- Weekly sprints following Agile method using Jira.

**Web Adventure** 

July 2022 Awards

- 2D Web-based game made using JavaScript, Kotlin, Spring Boot, and MySQL.
- Built reusable sprite animation using concepts of encapsulation and abstraction.
- User authentication using Spring Security and password encryption.

**Quack Manager** 

August 2020 - December 2020 Spring 2020

- University team project using Java, Android Studio, MySQL and Spring Boot.
- Implemented Front-end management of tasks, profile, login, and settings.
- Proactively stored data on device for fast offline access.

Technical Skills

Languages

**Proficient** 

C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Dart,

Python, MySQL

**Familiar** 

December 2022 Kotlin, PHP, C#

**Technologies** 

NumPy, Spring Boot, Firebase, Flutter, Node.js,

React

Software

Excel, Docker, Android

Studio

Soft Skills

**Critical Thinking Conflict Resolution** 

**Active Learning** 

Adaptability

Relevant Topics

Algorithm Design **Data Structures** 

**Computational Geometry** 

**Network Protocols** 

**Network Security** 

ISU Dean's List

Fall 2019 - Fall 2022

**Highest 2% LAS Freshman** 

**Highest 2% LAS Junior** 

*Spring 2021*